Daniel A. Pinedo

Strategic Human Resources

(215) 839-6299

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

SUMMARY

Daniel is entering the Strategic HR field with over a decade of prior experience in consulting, management, university teaching, and IT roles. His primary expertise is in forming, leading, and developing cross-disciplinary teams of specialists in order to complete mission-critical and time-sensitive human capital projects. An example area of focus is studying how inclusive workplaces spark innovation and intrapreneurship in firms.

His vision is to leverage an increased strategic role of human resources in organizations with the goal of connecting financial strategy with global recruitment and talent management in the United States and global markets.

Daniel finds joy in facilitating growth and development in employees as a trained and experienced executive and mindfulness coach.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Project Manager

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

10/2019 - Current

Global HR / Recruitment Transformation Research & Development Lab. Same duties as Consultant plus ownership of project timelines, milestones, and personnel time and task budgeting. Team sizes are 4-8 members per project.

• PROJECT: Documentation sprint for preparation of final presentation of completed and vetted global employee selection and assessment model to CHRO. Project completed at 70% time and 60% personnel budget.

Consultant

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

m 03/2019 - Current

Global HR / Recruitment Transformation Research & Development Lab. Same duties as Associate plus ownership of project deliverable content, translation of research into business case for internal clients, and engagement with primary stakeholder managers.

- · Member of Recruitment and Selection committee which planned recruitment events and created internal selection infrastructure
- Member of Fairness Committee which vetted projects and ensured fairness in internal selection and promotion
- · Member of Strategy Committee which steered organizational effectiveness and employee development programs and processes
- PROJECT: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into secondary implementation stage with global alignment teams
- PROJECT: SME and individual interviewer for values-based assessment prototype
- PROJECT: SME and focus group interviewer for selection assessment design prototype
- PROJECT: SME and consultant for leadership model synthesis and design

Associate

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

11/2018 - 03/2019

Global HR / Recruitment Transformation Research & Development Lab. Subject Matter Expert (SME) in organizational behavior, management, statistics, research methods, interviewing, and focus groups.

- PROJECT: Literature review for behavioral interview theory
- · PROJECT: SME for behavioral interview theory; initiated implementation plan with global management team
- PROJECT: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into pilot stage with global alignment teams

Statistical Consultant

Lisa Kaczmarczyk PhD Consulting, LLC

12/2019 12/2019

% http://www.lisakaczmarczyk.com/

Social Network Analysis with R programming language for client program evaluation spanning three [undisclosed] university systems.

• completion of a social network analysis of a cross-section of three attitudinal constructs across three universities including actor-event network graphs, interpretation consultation, and commented Rmarkdown script.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Management Consultant

Arup

% https://www.arup.com

Organizational effectiveness evaluation plan consultation team member for North America regional HR departments.

- Completed developmental and formative evaluation plan for new-hire on-boarding program across IT, HR, Facilities, and Finance Departments
- Provided recommendations to senior HR managers for program improvement and monitoring for turnover reduction, improved communication across departments, and productivity due to potential increase in employee engagement

Executive Coach

Getty Leadership Institute, LeAD Labs

1 05/2019 - 08/2019

% https://gli.cgu.edu/

Primary support for three senior international museum executives during leadership training and assessment center program.

- · Assisted clients in creation of development plan based on assessment center, 360°, and StrengthsFinder results
- Follow-up with each client 6-8 weeks following leadership program related to completion of specific SMART goals and creation of longterm professional development goals

Management Consultant

Undisclosed Property Management Firm

1 03/2019 - 06/2019

Organizational culture project for private, family-owned property management firm currently undergoing succession-related change with a portfolio of over \$1 billion in residential and commercial real-estate assets.

- · Diagnosed internal-facing stress related to values signaling from family management through executive management
- Provided business case for implementing values communications strategies with potential for increased organizational commitment and overall firm performance
- Connected business strategy with identified cultural values for implementation in management training program

Team Lead

BCG Gamma Datathon

Invite-only case competition for BCG data analytics group among graduate students from USC Marshall, UCLA Anderson, and CGU Drucker management schools.

- Recruited ad-hoc cross-functional team of experts in the fields of artificial intelligence, financial engineering, data science, management, and organizational behavior
- Provided case formulation training, strategy, and high-level architecture for technical solution

Management Consultant

ICM Partners

1 09/2018 - 01/2019

% icmpartners.com

Organizational behavior project for Top 5 creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring.

• 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new hire

EDUCATION

MA Psychology in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Claremont Graduate University

• Emphasis in Management

GPA
3.7 / 4.0

MA Clinical Psychology

Sofia University

2013 Palo Alto, CA

BA

Naropa University

COURSEWORK HIGHLIGHTS

Management

Financial Accounting Corporate Finance Economics of Strategy Macroeconomics

Organizational Behavior

Organizational Behavior Organizational Culture Organizational Theory

Statistics

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis Factor Analysis

Structural Equation Modeling

Programming

R C++ Java

PAST WORK EXPERIENCE

Mount Saint Mary's University (01/2016 - 05/2018)

Lecturer - Undergraduate faculty in psychology department developing and teaching courses in Research Methods, Social Psychology, Positive Psychology, and Organizational Psychology. Academic Counseling for 15 students.

Sovereign Health of California (08/2014 - 06/2015)

Clinician - Clinical Psychology internship for dual-diagnosis intensive outpatient / partial in-patient program.

Sofia University Electroencephalography Lab (09/2012 - 06/2013)

Interim Director / Manager - Academic EEG lab studying brainwave correlates of meditative states of consciousness.

Oversee.net (09/2007 - 08/2008)

Network Operations Engineer - monitoring and deployment of mission-critical, revenue generating network infrastructure.

IT Management Consultant (2005 - 2008)

Principal Consultant - Network security and IT management outsourcing.